Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers Relating to African American Arts and Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1914-1971; Series I; 26.6; 58 boxes
  - A-Z Correspondence
    - Robeson, Eslanda
      - 1934–1964 (Box 41, Folder 747-751)
        Includes autograph letters, signed, from Robeson to CVV, written on verso of eight photographs of buildings in Russia (1936); autograph letter, signed, from Eslanda C. Goode to CVV (1939?); autograph note, signed, from Robeson to CVV on verso of photograph of the Great Wall of China (1949)
    - Robeson, Paul, 1927-1945, undated (Box 41, Folder 752)
      Includes typed letter, signed, from Fanny Ellsworth to CVV (1938); form letter on Council on African Affairs, Inc. letterhead, signed by Robeson and Max Yergan to CVV (1945)
    - Robbs, Mary E., 1950 (Box 41, Folder 753)
    - Robinson, A'Lelia Walker, 1925–1931 (Box 41, Folder 754)
      Includes autograph letter, signed, from "Mamie" to CVV (1931)
    - Robinson, Bill, 1926–1950 (Box 41, Folder 755)
      Includes notes and letters signed by Fannie Robinson, Robinson's second wife; telegram from the Negro Actors Guild of America to CVV (1940); and invitation to the unveiling and dedication of the memorial monument to Robinson (1950)
    - Robinson, James H., 1951 January 25 (Box 41, Folder 756)
      Invitation to a tea presenting Rev. James H. Robinson
    - Robinson, Rachel, 1950 November 1 (Box 41, Folder 757)
      Form letter on behalf of the National Association of Colored Graduate Nurses
    - Robinson-Wayne, Beatrice, 1934–1964 (Box 41, Folder 758-759)
    - Rosette, Belle
      See: McBurnie, Beryl
    - Rudwick, Elliott M., 1954 May 1 (Box 41, Folder 760)
    - Salem Scholarship Foundation, 1943 May 10 (Box 41, Folder 761)
    - Sampson, Edith S. (Edith Spurlock), 1950–1956 (Box 41, Folder 762)
    - Savage, Archie
      See: Waters, Ethel
    - Savage, Augusta, 1938; 1940 (Box 41, Folder 763)
      Includes typed carbon copy letters to CVV from Oliver D. Williams and from Arthur B. Spingarn (1940)
    - Sayers, Emma Lue, 1927 January 24 (Box 41, Folder 764)
    - Scarlette, Portia B., 1950 July 25 (Box 41, Folder 765)
    - Schaffner, John, 1951 October 15 (Box 41, Folder 766)
      Regarding William Gardner Smith
    - Scholarship, 1947 November 13 (Box 41, Folder 767)
    - Schuyler, George S. (George Samuel), 1931–1969 (Box 41, Folder 768-769)
      Includes two typed letters, carbon copy, signed by Mozell C. Hill of Phyon, to Schuyler, with copy to CVV (1950); typescript list of recipients of Schuyler's article "The Van Vechten Revolution" with manuscript annotations by CVV (1950); photograph of the actors William Marshall and Anne Francis in Haiti (1952)
    - Schuyler, Josephine, 1946–1968 (Box 42, Folder 770-779)
      Includes typed letter, signed, from Verna Still to Schuyler, with autograph note by Schuyler on verso (1950); four cancelled checks to Schuyler from CVV and FM (1953-1954); photograph of Schuyler enclosed with autograph letter to CVV (1955); originals and copies of third-party letters to Schuyler regarding her daughter Philippa's musical career; photograph of Philippa Schuyler with Queen Elizabeth of Belgium enclosed with letter from Schuyler to CVV (1959)
    - Schuyler, Philippa, 1946-1964, undated (Box 43, Folder 780-783)
      Includes photograph of Schuyler and holiday greeting (1946); three undated photographs of Schuyler in Haiti and Surinam
    - Scott, Henry B., 1945–1946 (Box 43, Folder 784)
    - Scott, Harold, 1959; 1963 (Box 43, Folder 785)
      Includes third-party letters regarding Scott from May Dammond, and Susie Walker (1959)
    - Scott, Neil, 1949 May 25 (Box 43, Folder 786)
      Regarding James Edwards
    - Seabrook, Frederick V., undated (Box 43, Folder 787)
      Form letter with autograph manuscript note regarding the Black Christ Movement
    - Sebree, Charles, 1941; 1943; undated (Box 43, Folder 788)
    - Sexton, Gracia, 1957 November 30 (Box 43, Folder 789)
    - Shaw, Esther Popel, 1947 September 27 (Box 43, Folder 790)
    - Shaw, Eugene R., 1953–1963 (Box 43, Folder 791)
    - Sheean, Vincent
      See: Hunt, Juanita
    - Shereff, Dorothy L., 1955 June 7 (Box 43, Folder 792)
      Regarding Viking Press publication including a work by James Weldon Johnson
    - Shields, Vincent, 1959 May 15 (Box 43, Folder 793)
    - Shirley, George, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 794)
    - Short, Bobby, 1962–1964 (Box 43, Folder 795)
    - Showers, Pearl
      Includes correspondence from Showers' husband, Louis U. Showers
      - 1934–1952 (Box 43, Folder 796-799)
      - 1953-1964, undated (Box 44, Folder 800-803)
    - Silvera, John D., 1946 September 13 (Box 44, Folder 804)
    - Simms, Hilda, 1957 March 19 (Box 44, Folder 805)
      Telegram co-signed by Sammy Davis and Marc Connelly
    - Simms-St. Martini, Robert G., 1926 (Box 44, Folder 806)
    - Sissle, Noble, 1963, undated (Box 44, Folder 807)
    - Smallwood, William H., 1942; 1947 (Box 44, Folder 808)
    - Smith, Bessie, 1947–1964 (Box 44, Folder 809)
      Correspondence with Jazz Record magazine, Columbia Recording Corporation, Grove Press, and MacMillan Company regarding publication of CVV photographs of Bessie Smith and Clara Smith
    - Smith, Florence, 1952; 1955 (Box 44, Folder 810)
      Regarding Leontyne Price, student of Smith (who taught under her maiden name, Florence Kimball)
    - Smith, Lillian E., 1942; 1962 (Box 44, Folder 811)
      Includes form letter and brochure on behalf of the National Committee for a Sane Nuclear Policy (1962)
    - Smith, Lucy, 1954 (Box 44, Folder 812)
      Holiday card with poems by, and photograph of, Smith and Sarah E. Wright
    - Smith, Milt A., 1947 (Box 44, Folder 813)
    - Smith, T.B., 1931 August 24 (Box 44, Folder 814)
      Typed note, signed, from Smith to CVV, with typed letter, carbon copy, from Smith to James Hull enclosed
    - Smith, William Gardner, 1948–1959 (Box 44, Folder 815)
    - Smythe, Hugh H., 1947 January 31 (Box 44, Folder 816)
    - Spearman, Daisy L., 1955 (Box 44, Folder 817)
    - Spencer, Anne, 1943 (Box 44, Folder 818)
    - Spencer, J. DeWitt, 1945 (Box 44, Folder 819)
    - Spencer, Onah L., 1933 July 22 (Box 44, Folder 820)
      Typed letter, signed, from Spencer to CVV, with typescript table of contents for his manuscript, "The Romantic Evolution of Jazz"
    - Spicer, James, 1960 October 23 (Box 44, Folder 821)
      Regarding stage production of Jean Genet's The Blacks
    - Spielman, J.G., 1927 (Box 44, Folder 822)
    - Spingarn, Amy Einstein, 1942–1952 (Box 44, Folder 823)
    - Spingarn, Arthur B. (Arthur Barnett), 1926–1959 (Box 44, Folder 824)
      Includes bookplate designed by Aaron Douglas for the Arthur B. Spingarn Collection of Negro Literature enclosed with Spingarn's autograph note, signed, to CVV (1928)
    - Sterling, Philip, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 825)
      Regarding a biography of Bert Williams
    - Stevens, Ernest W., 1943 September 21 (Box 45, Folder 826)
    - Stevens, George William, 1945 November 12 (Box 45, Folder 827)
      Typed and autograph note from Langston Hughes to CVV regarding Stevens written on verso of envelope
    - Still, Verna Arvey
      See: Arvey, Verna
    - Still, William Grant, 1938–1960 (Box 45, Folder 828)
      Includes form letter, signed, from Newbold Morris of The City Center of Music and Drama Inc., regarding the opera Troubled Island, with text of "I Dream a World" by Langston Hughes enclosed (1944); newspaper clipping, photocopy, of Still's letter to the editor of the Arkansas Gazette (1952)
    - Stinette, McCleary, 1930–1947 (Box 45, Folder 829)
    - Stone, Roberta, 1940 February 28 (Box 45, Folder 830)
    - Stokes, Al, 1934 (Box 45, Folder 831)
    - Stone, Chuck, 1959 October 20 (Box 45, Folder 832)
    - Strange Fruit cast, 1946 January 21 (Box 45, Folder 833)
    - Strouse, Richard, 1948 April 9 (Box 45, Folder 834)
      Regarding Bill Robinson
    - Student Non-violent Coordinating Committee, 1963–1964 (Box 45, Folder 835)
    - Swanson, Howard, 1951–1953 (Box 45, Folder 836)
    - Taffs, J. Alan, 1951 June 2 (Box 45, Folder 837)
    - Tarry, Ellen, 1946–1955 (Box 45, Folder 838)
      Includes third-party correspondence from Viking Press regarding Tarry's publications (1946, 1950); The New American Library of World Literature regarding the reprint of James Weldon Johnson's The Autobiography of an Ex-Coloured Man (1948); and letters from Tarry to CVV on behalf of the James Weldon Johnson Literary Guild (1948, 1950)
    - Tate, Ernest C., 1948–1960 (Box 45, Folder 839)
    - Terrell, Mary Church, 1950 (Box 45, Folder 840)
    - Thayer, Alonzo, 1934–1935 (Box 45, Folder 841)
    - Thayer, Reba J., 1936 March 21 (Box 45, Folder 842)
    - Thomas, Carl Alan, 1945–1964 (Box 45, Folder 843)
    - Thomas, Edna, 1926 (Box 45, Folder 844-849)
      Includes correspondence regarding the Negro Actors Guild of America; telegram, notes and cards from Thomas, her husband, Lloyd Thomas, and Olivia Wyndham; typed note, signed by Robert Dowling to Thomas enclosed with autograph letter to Fania Marinoff (1965)
    - Thompkins, William, 1940 (Box 46, Folder 850)
    - Thornton, Mildred, 1944-1964, undated (Box 46, Folder 851)
    - Thurman, Wallace, 1927 [March?] (Box 46, Folder 852)
    - Toomer, Jean, 1925 March 9 (Box 46, Folder 853)
    - Torchlight Productions, Inc., 1949 (Box 46, Folder 854)
      Form letters, signed, by Jane White and David Kapralik
    - Towles, Lois, 1948 (Box 46, Folder 855)
    - Tuskegee Institute. Carver Research Foundation, 1944; 1949 (Box 46, Folder 856)
    - Tuttle, Charles E., 1941 October 29 (Box 46, Folder 857)
    - Tynes, Margaret, 1959–1960 (Box 46, Folder 858)
    - Urban League of Greater New York, 1958 (Box 46, Folder 859)
      Form letters, signed, by Ernestine H. Guess and Edward S. Lewis
    - Vail Library (Lincoln University), 1933–1940 (Box 46, Folder 860)
      Includes letters from Mary Fleming Labaree, Curator to CVV
    - Valentine, William R., 1932–1950 (Box 46, Folder 861)
      Includes letters signed by Valentine's wife, Grace Valentine, and third-party letters regarding the Manual Training and Industrial School for Colored Youth, Bordentown, New Jersey
    - Van Dyke, Henry, 1961-1964, undated (Box 46, Folder 862-864)
      Includes letters and postcards to Van Dyke from CVV
      Letters from CVV acquired from Henry Van Dyke, 1977
    - Verrett, Shirley, 1961; 1964 (Box 46, Folder 865)
    - Virtue, Hope McKay, 1948–1949 (Box 46, Folder 866)
      Includes postcard with photograph of Virtue (1949)
    - Von Hesse, Maxeda Ferguson, 1951 (Box 46, Folder 867)
      Regarding Von Hesse's "inter-racial relations project"
    - W. C. Handy Foundation for the Blind, 1951–1957 (Box 46, Folder 868-869)
      Includes meeting notices, minutes, reports and third-party correspondence regarding the organization
    - Wadleigh High School (New York, N.Y.). James Bowers Peterson Memorial Collection of Photographs of Celebrated Negroes by Carl Van Vechten, 1944-1951, undated (Box 47, Folder 870-874)
      Includes correspondence between CVV and Dorothy Peterson (a teacher at Wadleigh High School), regarding the Jerome Bowers Peterson Memorial Collection of Photograph of Celebrated Negroes by Carl Van Vechten; correspondence between Peterson, school administrators and others including Harold Jackman, Zora Neale Hurston, Aaron Douglas, William C. Handy, and others; typescript mimeograph copy of "American Negro Exhibit" at Syracuse University Library (1945); typescript carbon list of invitees to exhibit of photographs at Wadleigh High School (1948); typescript carbon lists of photographs within the Peterson Collection (1951, undated)
    - Walker, A'Lelia
      See: Robinson, A'Lelia Walker
    - Walker, Katie, 1949 June 24 (Box 47, Folder 875)
    - Walrond, Eric, 1925–1926 (Box 47, Folder 876)
    - Warfield, William C., 1951–1963 (Box 47, Folder 877)
      Includes invitation to wedding of Warfield and Leontyne Price (1952); autograph and typed letters, signed, from Larney Goodkind to CVV (1955-1958)
    - Warren, Masood Ali, 1950 April 9 (Box 47, Folder 878)
    - Washington, Fredi, 1938–1941 (Box 47, Folder 879)
    - Waters, Ethel, 1928–1964 (Box 47, Folder 880-882)
      Includes notes and letters from Pearl Wright (1933); Tommy Berry (1937); Archie Savage (1942-1943); Donna Wilson (1960); telegram from "Guthrie" to CVV and Fania Marinoff (1939)
    - Waters, James C., Jr., 1914 July 3 (Box 47, Folder 883)
      Accompanied by typed letter, carbon copy, signed, from Waters to the editor of the Literary Digest, with typed carbon memorandum
    - Watkins, Gordon, 1957 August 9 (Box 47, Folder 884)
    - Watkins, Perry, 1940–1941 (Box 47, Folder 885)
    - Watts, Mr., undated (Box 47, Folder 886)
      Typed and autograph draft of note to "Mr. Watts" from CVV
    - Weiss, Sigmund, 1947 June 14 (Box 47, Folder 887)
      Typed letter, signed, from bookseller Weiss, with list of books by Black authors on offer
    - Welch, Elizabeth, undated (Box 47, Folder 888)
      Autograph note from "Ethel" regarding Welch
    - Wellborn, Cecil W., 1958 December 20 (Box 47, Folder 889)
    - Wesley, Charles Floyd, 1943–1944 (Box 47, Folder 890)
    - Wesley, Louise J., 1959 February 18 (Box 47, Folder 891)
    - West, Dorothy, 1931–1948 (Box 47, Folder 892)
    - Westerman, George W., 1947; 1951 (Box 47, Folder 893)
      Includes typed letter, signed, from Florence Murray, editor of The Negro Handbook (1947)
    - Weston, M. Moran, 1961 (Box 47, Folder 894)
    - Wheeler, Charles Enoch, 1943–1963 (Box 47, Folder 895-896)
    - White, Carl Darrow, 1955–1964 (Box 48, Folder 897-898)
      Includes photographs of White and his family (1959, 1961-1963)
    - White, Clarence Cameron, 1942–1960 (Box 48, Folder 899)
    - White, Gladys, 1930–1965 (Box 48, Folder 900-901)
      Includes two telegrams co-signed by Gladys White and Walter White
    - White, Jane, 1941–1962 (Box 48, Folder 902)
      Includes typed letter, carbon copy, of letter from Jane White to Jane Cowl of the Stage Door Canteen enclosed with letter to CVV (1945)
    - White, Mattie H., 1947 (Box 48, Folder 903)
    - White, Poppy Cannon
      See: Cannon, Poppy
    - White, Walter
      Includes correspondence between White and CVV and third-party correspondents as well as documents relating to the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP)
      See also: James Weldon Johnson Memorial Committee
      - 1924–1934 (Box 48, Folder 904-907)
        Includes original and carbon copies of letters to and/or from the Victor Talking Machine Company regarding Paul Robeson recordings (1925); Henry Allen Moe of the Guggenheim Foundation (1926); Hale Woodruff (1927, 1930); Mary W. Ovington (1927); and Hunter Stagg to James Weldon Johnson (1934); and letters regarding the Sabbath Glee Club (1924)
      - 1935–1952 (Box 49, Folder 908-911)
        Includes original and carbon copies of letters to and/or from Van Vechten Shaffer (1937); Henry R. Luce (1939); Clarence Cameron White (1940); and Robert C. Weaver (1941)
    - Who's Who in America, 1939 February 22 (Box 49, Folder 912)
      Regarding Ethel Waters and Marian Anderson
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1950–1964 (Box 49, Folder 913)
      Regarding the American Council and African Education and the NAACP
    - Wilkinson, Henry Bertram, 1955 June 24 (Box 49, Folder 914)
    - Williams, Billy Dee, 1963 February 7 (Box 49, Folder 915)
    - Williams, Burton D., 1961 May 12 (Box 49, Folder 916)
    - Williams, Camilla, 1946–1964 (Box 49, Folder 917)
    - Williams, John A., 1962–1964 (Box 49, Folder 918)
    - Williams, Ned E., 1933 February 7 (Box 49, Folder 919)
      Regarding photographs of Cab Calloway
    - Williams, Paul R., 1936–1937 (Box 49, Folder 920)
    - Williams, Thomas M., 1952 July 30 (Box 49, Folder 921)
      Death and funeral notice
    - Williams, Wilson A., 1942 October 15 (Box 49, Folder 922)
      Regarding the Negro Dance Company
    - Wilson, Ellis, 1948–1960 (Box 49, Folder 923)
    - Wilson, F.H., 1926 July 5 (Box 49, Folder 924)
    - Wilson, Miriam B., 1951 August 19 (Box 49, Folder 925)
      Accompanied by typescript, carbon copy, of Wilson's work on the Old Slave Mart Museum project
    - Wilson, Thomas, 1959 May 26 (Box 49, Folder 926)
      Regarding recordings of "God's Trombones" by United Artists Records
    - Woodbeck, Wilson W., 1964 March 12 (Box 49, Folder 927)
      Form letter on behalf of the National Association of Negro Musicians
    - Woode, Lenn, 1943 (Box 49, Folder 928)
    - Woodruff, Hale, 1932 October 26 (Box 49, Folder 929)
    - Work, F. J., 1940 February 27 (Box 49, Folder 930)
    - Worrell, Emma H., 1946 May 2 (Box 49, Folder 931)
    - Worthy, O. Ernestine, 1948–1951 (Box 49, Folder 932)
    - Wreden, Nicholas R., 1951 December 20 (Box 49, Folder 933)
      Letter from Wreden, editor-in-chief at E. P. Dutton, regarding Lonnie Coleman's book, Clara
    - Wright, Corinne, 1934–1952 (Box 49, Folder 934)
    - Wright, Dale R., 1951–1952 (Box 49, Folder 935)
    - Wright, Michael, 1952–1956 (Box 49, Folder 936)
    - Wright, Richard, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 937)
    - Wright, Sara E., 1955 December 20 (Box 49, Folder 938)
    - Wright, Stephen J., 1960–1964 (Box 49, Folder 939)
    - Wyndham, Olivia, 1936–1963 (Box 49, Folder 940)
    - Young, George, 1928 February 3 (Box 49, Folder 941)
      Accompanied by printed advertisement for Young's Book Exchange
    - Young Men's Christian Association of Greater New York, Harlem Branch, 1962 (Box 49, Folder 942)
      Form letter, signed, by Hubert T. Delany, with autograph note from Hilda Haynes on bottom of letter
    - Youngblood, John W., 1931 September 26 (Box 49, Folder 943)
      Regarding The Liberator
    - Zaidins, Earle Warren, 1958 December 10 (Box 49, Folder 944)
      Regarding Althea Gibson
    - Zangrando, Robert L., 1962–1963 (Box 49, Folder 945)
  - Copies of Letters in Carl Van Vechten Papers From the New York Public Library
    - Chesnutt, Charles W., 1926 (Box 50, Folder 946)
      Letters to CVV
    - Johnson, Charles Spurgeon, 1926 August 10 (Box 50, Folder 947)
      Letter to CVV
    - Johnson, James Weldon, 1925–1932 (Box 50, Folder 948)
  - Christmas Cards
    - 1925–1938 (Box 51, Folder 949-962)
    - 1939–1945 (Box 52, Folder 963-969)
    - 1946–1950 (Box 53, Folder 970-974)
    - 1951–1955 (Box 54, Folder 975-979)
    - 1956-1958, undated (Box 55, Folder 980-983)
  - Advertising Cards, Invitations to Clubs, Balls, and Restaurants
    - circa 1925-1944 (Box 56, Folder 984-986)
- Writings, 1925-1964; Series II; 5.51; 7 boxes
  Writings includes manuscripts, typescripts, proofs, clippings, and other material documenting Van Vechten's books, articles and essays, reviews, addresses and speeches, etc. about Black artists and writers. In addition to manuscripts, typescripts, and proofs of his writings, related notes, correspondence, clippings of published writings, and other material is included. Van Vechten's unpublished list of books and manuscripts donated to Yale, "James Weldon Johnson Memorial Collection of Negro Arts and Letters Founded by Carl Van Vechten," and a listing of miscellaneous correspondence and writings of Walter White are also included. The subseries Writings by Others includes works written by Black writers including Nora Hold, Langston Hughes, and James Weldon Johnson. The works include essays in honor of Van Vechten, typescripts of works (some of which are inscribed to Van Vechten), and a leaf of an autograph manuscript of Up From Slavery by Booker T. Washington, a 50th wedding anniversary gift to Van Vechten and his wife by Donald Gallup. Also included are transcripts of radio broadcasts of Fania Marinoff's remarks on racial prejudice.
  Organized into seven subseries: Books, Articles and Essays, Reviews, Addresses and Speeches, Lists, Notes, and Writings by Others. Within these subseries, Van Vechten's writings are arranged alphabetically by title. Writings by Others are arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Books
    - Nigger Heaven
      - Notes, undated (Box 59, Folder 993)
        Includes typescript notes by CVV
      - Alterations suggested by Langston Hughes for seventh printing, undated (Box 59, Folder 994)
        Includes corrections and inserts of songs written by Hughes, with autograph annotations by CVV
      - Notes and suggestions for alterations, 1941; undated (Box 59, Folder 995)
        Includes autograph notes by Rudolph Fisher, J. Rosamond Johnson, and James Weldon Johnson
      - Alterations appearing in the seventh printing
        - Notes and page proofs, 1926 (Box 59, Folder 996-997)
          Includes autograph notes by CVV indicating corrections with corresponding page numbers; page proofs of corrected pages, with autograph corrections by CVV
        - Plate proof, 1926 (Box 65 (Oversize), Folder 1094)
          Plate proof of alterations signed by Langston Hughes; stamped "The Plimpton Press Norwood Mass"
      - Foundry proof, 1926 (Box 65 (Oversize), Folder 1095)
        Includes autograph manuscript corrections by CVV
      - Plate proof for illustrated edition, 1931 (Box 64 (Oversize), Folder 1087)
        Includes typed note from CVV to Mr. Stimson outlining changes to be made to the existing plates (1931 March 10); stamped "The Plimpton Press, Norwood Mass."
      - "A Belated Introduction", 1950, undated (Box 59, Folder 998)
        Three drafts, typescript with autograph corrections signed by CVV of the introduction to the 1951 Avon edition
      - Reviews, 1926; 1928 (Box 59, Folder 999-1000)
      - Excerpts from reviews, undated (Box 59, Folder 1001)
        Typescript exceprts from reviews, for possible publicity blurbs
      - Correspondence
        - Avon Publishing Co. Inc., 1950–1951 (Box 59, Folder 1002)
          Regarding Avon edition of Nigger Heaven
        - Bissell, Clifford H., 1927 January 27 (Box 59, Folder 1003)
          Autograph letter to CVV regarding inacurracy in Nigger Heaven
        - Kauffer, Edward McKnight, 1930–1947 (Box 59, Folder 1004)
          Correspondence chiefly relating to illustrations for a deluxe edition
  - Articles and Essays
    - "A'Lelia Walker", 1927 (Box 60, Folder 1005)
      Typescript draft, corrected, signed by CVV with note "unfinished and unpublished"
    - "The Black Blues", 1925 June 4 (Box 60, Folder 1006)
      Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, and clipping, Vanity Fair
    - "Carl Van Vechten Comments", 1934 February 27 (Box 60, Folder 1007)
      Drafts, typescript, corrected; with 1934 September issue of Challenge
    - "Clara Smith", 1947 (Box 60, Folder 1008)
      Drafts, typescripts, corrected
    - [Clément Richer], undated (Box 60, Folder 1009)
      Drafts, typescript original and carbon, corrected
    - "Concerning Richmond Barthé", 1939 (Box 60, Folder 1010)
      Drafts, typescript, corrected; with Arden Gallery catalog and clippings
    - "Countee Cullen", 1925 April 3 (Box 60, Folder 1011)
      Draft, typescript carbon, corrected
    - [Ethel Waters], 1939 (Box 60, Folder 1012)
      Draft, typescript, corrected, of text of advertisement written by CVV on behalf of himself and several others for The New York Times regarding the performance of Ethel Waters in Mamba's Daughters in response to a negative review by Brooks Atkinson; with clippings from The New York Times
    - "The Folksongs of the American Negro"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1925 May 7 (Box 60, Folder 1013)
      - Clipping, Vanity Fair, 1926 February (Box 64 (Oversize), Folder 1088)
    - "Foreward" to Born to Be, by Taylor Gordon, 1939 August 29 (Box 60, Folder 1014)
      Drafts, typescript, corrected
    - "A Great Spirit", 1947 (Box 60, Folder 1015)
      Essay on Marian Anderson, drafts, typescript, corrected, with autograph notes